Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/wohlreich (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Public Speaking
Team Organisation
Microsoft Office

Languages

French (Elementary)

David Wohlreich

VP, Total Rewards @ Twitch

Menlo Park, California, United States

Summary

I've worked across industries and geographies, in operations, HR, and finance, from 250 employees to 390,000. It's always - always - the people and the culture which make a job anything more than a grind.

I have opinions about everything but answers about very little.

There's almost always a better way to do things. Let's find it together.

Experience

Twitch
VP, Total Rewards
July 2022 - Present (2 months)
San Francisco, California, United States

Front

1 year 1 month

Head of People Experience & Operations January 2022 - July 2022 (7 months) San Francisco Bay Area

At the intersection of the organization and the individual, the culture and the systems, we try to make work a little better, a little easier, a little more sensible, and a little more just. And have a lot of fun in the process.

Head of People Operations

July 2021 - January 2022 (7 months)

San Francisco, California, United States

Building a people infrastructure worthy of the folks making work happier by meaningfully connecting teams and customers

Niantic, Inc.

2 years 4 months

Director, Total Rewards & HR Operations January 2020 - March 2021 (1 year 3 months)

Page 1 of 6

San Francisco

Led the combined HR Operations function, representing Compensation, Benefits, HR Information Systems, HR Analytics, and Onboarding

Built a best-in-class employee experience, balancing financial constraints, cultural values, business strategy, and geographic, employee, & industry diversity

Built and managed the Rewards and HR Operations teams, recruiting, coaching, and developing individual contributors and managers across the subfunctions

Senior Manager, Compensation and Benefits December 2018 - January 2020 (1 year 2 months) San Francisco, California

Defined Niantic's employee value proposition (EVP)

Led Total Rewards strategy and function globally, including strategic design, analysis, and execution of all aspects of compensation (base salary, bonus, sales rewarding, equity)

Redesigned benefits and global mobility programs ensuring market competitiveness, cost efficiency, and alignment with business strategy and company values

Served as Niantic's subject matter expert in the field of Total Rewards, providing internal and external thought leadership on all aspects of rewards design, practice, and analysis

Riot Games

2 years

Manager, Global Compensation May 2017 - November 2018 (1 year 7 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Led global compensation function at Riot Games, hiring, training, and overseeing a team of compensation analysts to provide consulting and oversight directly and through HR business partners in the US and abroad

Managed global compensation programs at Riot, including role classification, compensation reviews, interdisciplinary and international mobility cases

Designed, implemented, and administered compensation infrastructure policies and programs to analyze market positions, identify opportunities or threats, and ensure total rewards strategy supports and advances company strategy

Served as ultimate compensation subject matter expert for the organization, providing expertise and analysis on demand and as part of cyclical budget and headcount reporting to function heads and senior executives

Designed and delivered robust compensation training and resources for executives, managers, and employees across Riot

Senior Compensation Analyst December 2016 - May 2017 (6 months)

Greater Los Angeles Area

Supported global compensation programs at Riot, including role classification, compensation reviews, interdisciplinary and international mobility cases

Designed, implemented, and administered compensation infrastructure policies and programs to analyze market positions and align with organizational strategic objectives

Served as compensation subject matter expert for HR and finance, providing expertise and analysis on demand and as part of cyclical budget and headcount reporting

Designed and delivered compensation training for managers and executives across Riot

Chubb (formerly ACE Group)
Senior Compensation Analyst
August 2015 - December 2016 (1 year 5 months)
Philadelphia, PA

Managed, developed and administered Chubb global compensation programs, with a focus on the Overseas General global group

Managed the annual global compensation cycle, including developing bonus and equity pools, analyzing year-over-year growth, managing the compensation planning system, and preparing detailed analyses/reports of compensation spend

Collaborated with HR leaders and the business to explore problems, resolve issues, and create solutions on matters related to the global compensation program

Conducted job evaluations by working closely with HR business partners to review job descriptions and ensure appropriate grade relative to internal and external comparisons utilizing market pricing and a job grading evaluation methodology

Conductes detailed market analyses for North America and other divisions (including international) to ensure market competitiveness of Chubb compensation practices

Oversaw the salary survey process, including managing vendor relationships, coordinating global participation with HR colleagues in relevant countries, and completing US salary survey submissions

Conductes quarterly analyses on headcount growth and compensation costs globally

Bosch North America

3 years 3 months

Compensation Analyst

November 2013 - August 2015 (1 year 10 months)

Farmington Hills, MI USA

Planned and executed Bosch's annual salary reviews and incentive programs representing a population of 9,000 associates and program budgets in excess of \$70 million

Evaluated and utilized external market pricing tools, including annual salary survey participation

Served as subject matter expert in compensation for Bosch's 1,500 midand senior-level managers, consulting internally on issues of market pricing, internal equity, and incentive structure

Drove continuous improvement in compensation for the region, supporting HR Business Partners representing 26,000 Bosch associates across North America

Designed and maintained compensation internal controls in coordination with internal and external auditors

Managed compensation topics for divestiture activities in the United States

Financial Analyst, Diesel Systems
June 2013 - November 2013 (6 months)

Performed product cost control, developed new standard costs, and analyzed impacts on product cost.

Maintained financial systems (SAP) and communicated data to senior management.

Delivered historical and forecast financial reports to plant management.

Financial Analyst

December 2012 - June 2013 (7 months)

Farmington Hills, MI

Supported controlling processes for month-end closing

Analyzed financial impact of new capital investments

Designed and executed engineering manager financial literacy training

Financial Analyst - Bosch Rexroth

June 2012 - December 2012 (7 months)

Bethlehem, PA

Audited internal controls effectiveness and compliance

Controlled and forecast employee and temporary/contingent worker headcount

Analyzed fixed asset acquisition return on investment

Indiana University School of Nursing

Resource Management Analyst

November 2011 - May 2012 (7 months)

Performed cost and cost driver analysis regarding salary and administration

data

Prepared documentation for scenario analysis

Communicated principles of activity-based costing to non-accounting

department heads

Kelley School of Business, Indiana University, Indianapolis

Teaching Assistant, A100 Basic Accounting Skills

August 2011 - May 2012 (10 months)

Co-taught review sessions

Ensured integrity and accuracy of student grades

Answered course and content questions for students

Henson Company

Summer Accounting/Finance Intern

May 2010 - August 2010 (4 months)

Assisted staff accountants with external audit support

Prepared budget and participation reports for quarterly board meetings

Performed account research, analysis, and reconciliation.

Various Companies

Office Manager and others

January 2001 - May 2010 (9 years 5 months)

Indianapolis, Indiana, United States

Held various positions in the hospitality and restaurant industry, working across front-of-house (server, bartender) and back-of-house (line cook, prep cook, expeditor, grill cook, office manager). Focused on casual theme and bar management.

Education

Indiana University - Kelley School of Business
Bachelor of Science in Business (Honors), Accounting, Finance, International
Studies · (2008 - 2012)